world is getting down with mCP right now
现在似乎全世界的开发者都在追捧
model context protocol is the hot new
模型上下文协议（mCP），它是
way to build apis and if you don't know
构建 API 的热门新方法。如果你不知道
what that is you're ngmi people are
它是什么，那你真是太落伍了。人们正在
doing crazy things with it like this guy
用它做出各种疯狂的事情，比如有人
powered entirely on Vibes and just a few
完全基于 Vibes 协议，用 Blender 设计 3D 艺术品。就在
days ago it became an official standard
几天前，它还成为了
in the open AI agents SDK if you're an
OpenAI Agents SDK 的官方标准。如果你是
OG subscriber to this channel you
本频道的忠实订阅者，你
probably know what a rest API is you
可能知道 REST API 是什么，甚至可能
might even know about graphql or RPC or
听说过 GraphQL 或 RPC，或者
maybe many years ago you use soap when I
很多年前你用过 SOAP。我
was a kid the software engineering
小时候，软件工程界的“
Gatekeepers told me I couldn't be a web
守门人”告诉我，
developer unless I could explain the
除非我能解释清楚
difference between these architectures
这些架构
and protocols well now the turns have
和协议之间的区别，否则就不能成为一名 Web 开发者。现在风水轮流转，
tabled and these Gatekeepers have been
这些“守门人”已经被
utterly demolished because we're all
彻底击溃，因为我们
just Vibe coders now embracing the
现在都是 Vibe 程序员，拥抱
exponentials pretending code doesn't
指数级增长，假装代码根本不
even exist and just chilling with llms
存在，只是用 LLM 轻松
until we get the end result we're
完成最终目标。也就是说，
call yourself a true vibe coder unless
除非你了解 Vibe 协议，否则你不能称自己为真正的 Vibe 程序员。
you know about model context protocol
关于模型上下文协议（mCP），
which is basically a new standard for
它本质上是
building apis that you can think of like
构建 API 的新标准，你可以把它想象成
a USBC port for AI application it was
AI 应用的 USB-C 接口。它由
Claud and provides a standard way to
Claud 背后的团队 Anthropico 设计，提供了一种为
give large language models context and
大型语言模型赋予上下文的标准方法。
they're so bullish on this technology
他们对这项技术非常看好，
that the CEO of anthropic said he
以至于 Anthropico 的 CEO 表示，他
expects virtually all code to be written
预计到今年年底，几乎所有代码都将由
by AI by the end of the year in today's
AI 编写。在今天的
video we'll actually build an mCP server
视频中，我们将实际构建一个 mCP 服务器，
and find out if it can truly make the
看看它是否真的能够
world a better place by eliminating all
通过消除所有
white collar jobs it is March 31st 2025
白领工作来让世界变得更美好。现在是 2025 年 3 月 31 日，
and you're watching the code report
你正在观看代码报告。与
contrary to popular belief a Fire Ship
普遍的看法相反，“火船”
is still a tutorial channel in today's
仍然是一个教程频道。在今天的
video we'll take a storage bucket a
视频中，我们将使用一个存储桶、一个
postgress database and a regular rest
PostgreSQL 数据库和一个常规的 REST
API and then connect them all together
API，然后使用
with the model context protocol not only
模型上下文协议将它们连接起来。
will this allow Claude to have access to
这不仅允许 Claude 访问
data it didn't have before but it can
它以前没有的数据，
also execute code on our server like
还可以执行服务器上的代码，例如
write to the database or upload files
写入数据库或上传文件。
and people of the internet are already
互联网上的用户已经在
using it to do crazy stuff like
使用它来做一些疯狂的事情，例如
automated ston and shitcoin trading
自动化的 Stone 和 Shitcoin 交易、
industrial scale web scraping and as a
工业级的网络爬虫等等。 作为
tool to manage Cloud infrastructure like
管理云基础设施（例如
your kubernetes cluster speaking of
Kubernetes 集群）的工具，说到
which to build our own mCP server we'll
构建我们自己的 mCP 服务器，我们
need some Cloud infrastructure and one
需要一些云基础设施，而
of the best places to do that is savola
Savola 是最佳选择之一。Savola
which itself is powered by Google
本身由 Google
kubernetes engine and cloudflare under
Kubernetes Engine 和 Cloudflare 提供支持。
the hood they were nice enough to
他们慷慨地
sponsor this video but the reason I like
赞助了本视频，但我
their platform so much is that it's far
如此喜欢他们的平台的原因是，它
easier to use than something like AWS
比 AWS 之类的服务更容易使用，
but provides linear predictable pricing
并且提供线性可预测的定价，这与
unlike most of the application and
大多数应用程序和
database hosting startups out there and
数据库托管初创公司不同。此外，它是
it's free to get started which makes it
免费的，这使它非常
perfect for this project now like other
适合本项目。与其他
API architectures mCP has a client in a
API 架构一样，mCP 也包含一个客户端和一个
server the client in our case will be
服务器。在本例中，客户端将是
claw desktop then will'll develop a
Claw Desktop。我们将开发一个
server that maintains a connection with
服务器来维护与
that client so the client and server can
该客户端的连接，以便客户端和服务器可以
pass information back and forth via the
通过传输层来回传递信息。
transport layer now in arrest API you
在 Resert API 中，
that you can send requests to Via
您可以使用许多不同的 HTTP 动词通过
different URLs but in the model context
不同的 URL 发送请求，但在模型上下文
protocol we're really only concerned
协议中，我们真正关心的只有
with two main things resources and tools
两件事：资源和工具。
a resource might be a file a database
资源可以是文件、数据库
query or some other information the
查询或
model can use for context conceptually
模型可用于上下文的其他信息。从概念上讲，
you can think of it like a git request
您可以…… 你可以把它想象成 Git 请求
and rest meanwhile a tool is an action
和 REST，而工具则是一种
that can be performed like writing
可以执行的操作，比如
something to a database so that'd be
向数据库写入数据，这
more like a poster request and rest what
更像是海报请求和 REST。
we do as developers is Define tools and
作为开发者，我们所做的就是在服务器上定义工具和
resources on the server is so the llm
资源，这样 LLM 系统
can automatically identify and use them
就能在需要它们时自动识别并使用它们。就我个人而言，
in my life I've been working on an app I
我一直在开发一款我视为巅峰之作的应用程序，
consider my magnum opus called horse
叫做“马匹护理员”（Horse
tender but as it turns out swiping left
Tender）。但事实证明，左右滑动
and right was a bad feature idea because
是个糟糕的功能，因为
horses don't have fingers so like every
马没有手指。所以，就像
other failing startup in Silicon Valley
硅谷其他失败的创业公司一样，
right now we're going to Pivot to
我们也要转型到
artificial intelligence luckily we can
人工智能领域。幸运的是，我们可以
leverage our existing data and servers
利用现有的数据和服务器。
like here in savola I have a storage
比如在 Savola，我有一个存储
bucket and it contains all of the photos
桶，里面存放着
that my users uploaded in addition for
用户上传的所有照片。此外，
user data we have a postgress database
我们还有一个 PostgreSQL 数据库，里面存储着
it has all the profile data for each one
每匹马的个人资料
of our horses as well as the
以及
relationships they form together and
它们之间的关系。
then finally I have a traditional rest
最后，我还有一个用
API written in typescript that fetches
TypeScript 编写的传统 REST API，用于
this data for my web IOS and Android
为我的 Web、iOS 和 Android 应用获取这些数据。
apps and what's especially cool about my
我的
code is that it's in a git repo hooked
代码最酷的地方在于…… 它位于一个
up to a cicd pipeline that means after
连接到 CICD 流水线的 Git 仓库中，这意味着在
we write our model context protocol
我们编写完模型上下文协议
server we can push our code to the dev
服务器后，我们可以将代码推送到开发
or staging branches to test it before it
或预发布分支进行测试，然后再将其部署
actually goes into production while
到生产环境。CICD 会
automatically handles all the
自动处理所有
deployments and cash busting for us
部署和维护工作。
automatically and now we're ready to
现在，我们准备开始编写
jump into some code here I have a dino
代码。我这里有一个 Dino
project and the first thing you'll
项目，首先你会
notice is that I'm importing a class
注意到我导入了一个
called mCP server this comes from the
名为 mCP 服务器的类。它来自
official SDK but if you're not using
官方 SDK，但如果你不使用
typescript they have a bunch of other
TypeScript，他们还提供了许多其他
languages like python Java and so on
语言的版本，例如 Python、Java 等。
we'll also be using Zod here which is a
我们还会使用 Zod，这是一个
tool used for schema validation which
用于模式验证的工具，它
allows us to provide a specific data
允许我们为 LLM 提供特定的数据
shape to the llm is so it doesn't just
结构，这样它就不会
hallucinate a bunch of random crap now
随意生成一堆乱码。
after we create a server we can start
创建服务器后，我们就可以开始向
adding resources to it the resource will
其中添加资源了。资源
first have a name like horses looking
首先会有一个名称，例如“寻找
for love and then the second argument is
爱情的马”，然后第二个参数是
a URI for the resource then finally the
资源的 URI，最后
third argument is a callback function
第三个参数是一个回调函数，
that we can use to fetch the data in
我们可以用它来获取数据。在
this example I'm writing a query to our
这个例子中，我正在编写一个 查询托管
postgress database which is hosted in
在
the cloud on savola then accessed on the
Savola 云端的 PostgreSQL 数据库，然后在
server with the postgress JS library but
服务器上使用 PostgreSQL JS 库访问。虽然
you could access any data here when
您可以在这里访问任何资源数据，但
something is a resource though it should
它应该
only be used for fetching data where
仅用于获取
there's no side effects or computations
没有副作用或计算的数据。
if you do have a side effect or
如果您确实有副作用或
computation you should instead use a
计算，则应该使用像
tool like for horse tender we might want
Horse Tender 这样的工具。我们可能希望
the AI to automatically create matches
AI 自动创建匹配
and set up dates between horses we
并安排马匹之间的日期。我们
already have a restful API endpoint that
已经有一个
can handle that and we could actually
可以处理此操作的 RESTful API 端点，我们可以
leverage that code here essentially
利用该代码，本质上是
creating an API for our API in fact many
为我们的 API 创建了一个 API。事实上，许多
of these mCP servers are actually just
mCP 服务器实际上只是 API 的 API，
apis for apis and that sounds like dumb
这听起来像是过度
over engineering but having a protocol
设计，但拥有
like this makes it a lot easier to Plug
这样的协议可以更轻松地在
and Play between different models and
不同模型之间进行即插即用，
just makes llm apps more reliable in
并使 LLM 应用程序总体上更可靠。
general the case in point notice how I'm
例如，请注意我是如何在
using Zod here to validate the shape of
这里使用 Zod 来验证
the data going into this function that
输入到此函数的数据格式的，这可以
prevents the llm from hallucinating
防止 LLM 产生
random stuff here basically when you
随机的幻觉。基本上，当您
prompt Claud it's going to need to
提示 Claud 时，它需要
figure out the proper arguments to this
确定此函数的正确参数，
function is so providing data types
因此需要提供数据类型。
along with a description will make your
添加描述将大大提高您的
mCP server far more reliable and then
mCP 服务器的可靠性，
the final step is to run the server in
最后一步是运行服务器。在
this case I'm going to use standard IO
本例中，我将使用标准 I/O
as the transport layer to use it locally
作为传输层，以便在本地使用。
but if deploy to the cloud you can also
但如果部署到云端，您还可以
use server sent events or HTTP
使用服务器发送事件 (SEST) 或 HTTP。
congratulations you just built an mCP
恭喜您，您刚刚构建了一个 mCP
server but now the question is how do we
服务器！但现在的问题是，我们如何
Act actually use it to use it you'll now
实际使用它？要使用它，您
need a client that supports the model
需要一个支持模型
context protocol like Claude desktop
上下文协议 (mCP) 的客户端，例如 Claude Desktop。
there if you don't want to use CLA
如果您不想使用 Claude
desktop like cursor and wisor for
Desktop，还有许多其他 mCP 客户端可供选择，例如 Cursor and Wisor。
example and you could even develop your
您甚至可以开发
own client but that's an entirely
自己的客户端，但这完全是
separate topic altogether once installed
另一个话题。安装完成后，
you can go to the developer settings
您可以进入开发者设置，
which will bring you to a config file
这将带您进入一个配置文件，
where you can add multiple mCP servers
您可以在其中添加多个 mCP 服务器。
in the config file all you have to do is
在配置文件中，您只需
provide a command to run the actual
提供一个命令来运行实际的
server which in our case would be the
服务器，在本例中，就是
doo command for the main.ts file where
针对 main.ts 文件的 doo 命令，该文件包含
we find our server code you'll need to
我们的服务器代码。您需要
restart clad but then it should show
重启 Claude Desktop，之后它应该会显示
your mCP server is running in this case
您的 mCP 服务器正在运行。在本例中，
my horse is running which means I should
我的马正在运行，这意味着我应该可以运行了。
probably go and catch
去抓住
it then you can go back to the prompt
它，然后你就可以返回提示
screen to attach it that's going to
屏幕并附加它。这将从
fetch the resource from the server so
服务器获取资源，以便
CLA can use it as context in the next
CLA 可以在下一个提示中将其用作上下文。
prompt and because clae is multimodal
由于 CLA 是多模态的，
you could also add PDFs images or
你还可以将 PDF、图像或
anything else to the context really like
任何其他内容添加到上下文中，例如
all the horse images in our Savala
我们 Savala 存储桶中的所有马匹图像。
storage bucket and now magically you can
现在，神奇的是，你可以
prompt Claude about things specific to
向 Claude 提示与
your application like if we want to find
你的应用程序相关的特定内容。例如，如果我们想
out which horses are single and ready to
知道哪些马匹是单身且准备
mingle we can make a prompt like this
交配，我们可以创建一个这样的提示，
and it will use the context that we just
它将使用我们刚刚
fetched from our database then if we
从数据库中获取的上下文。如果我们
want Claude to write to the database we
想让 Claude 写入数据库，我们
could make a prompt like this where
可以创建一个这样的提示，
it'll connect two horses from the
它将根据上下文中的日期连接两匹马。
context on a date you'll need to Grant a
你需要授予
permission to do this and then Claude
权限才能执行此操作，然后 Claude
will automatically figure out which data
将
to send it but based on the schema we
根据我们
validated with Zod and it'll use our
与 Zod 验证的模式自动确定要发送哪些数据，它将使用我们的
server tool to mutate data in the actual
服务器工具来修改实际
application I can't imagine anything
应用程序中的数据。我无法想象
ever possibly going wrong here and
这里会出什么问题，而且
anthropic is extremely bullish on this
Anthropico 对它的
being the future like their CEO just
未来充满信心，就像他们的 CEO 刚才
said that 90% of coding will be done
说的那样。 未来六个月内，90% 的编码工作将
entirely by AI within the next 6 months
完全由人工智能完成；
within a year I'm going to go ahead and
一年内，几乎所有代码都将由人工智能生成。我对此表示
press X to doubt there and I think it's
怀疑，我认为
only a matter of time before some AI
人工智能
agent accidentally wipes out billions of
代理意外删除价值数十亿
dollars in customer data or becomes
美元的客户数据，或者产生
self-aware and just deletes the data for
自我意识并出于好玩而删除数据，只是时间问题。
fun that being said though there's all
话虽如此，目前有很多基于 mCP 的
kinds of amazing tools being built with
出色工具正在开发中，
mCP right now and you can check those
你可以
out on the awesome mCP repo just please
在 mCP 的优秀代码库中查看这些工具。请务必
make sure to Vibe code responsibly huge
负责任地进行 Vibe 编码。非常
thanks to Savala for making this video
感谢 Savala 让这段视频得以制作，
possible and enjoy this $50 stimulus
并感谢他们提供的 50 美元奖励金，让你
check to try out their awesome platform
体验他们出色的平台。
this has been the code report thanks for
以上就是代码报告，感谢
watching and I will see you in the next
观看，我们下期再见！